Guide to the Time Inc. Invitational Records 1982-1989 MS 3009-RG 29
New-York Historical Society
Time Inc. Invitational Records
1982-1989
New-York Historical Society
Time, inc.
MS 3009-RG 29
10 Linear feet in 9 record cartons, 2 flat boxes
The Time Inc. Invitational was an annual invitation-only sports competition event organized by the magazines' Advertising Sales Departments and held at the Maidstone Club in East Hamptons, NY. Records include the planning and event materials for the years 1983 to 1985, 1987, and 1989.
Historical Note
The Time Inc. Invitational was an annual invitation-only sports competition event organized by the magazines' Advertising Sales Departments and held at the Maidstone Club in East Hamptons, NY. The "History" folder contains a memorandum from 1982 regarding that year's invitational indicating 1982 was not the first year for the event although the records do not disclose the first year.
A different magazine's Advertising Sales Department organized the event each year. Money organized the Invitational in 1983, Time organized it in 1984, Sports Illustrated organized it in 1985, People organized it in 1987, and Fortune organized it in 1989. The Invitational featured golf and tennis events, and was hosted by Time Inc.'s executive vice president, the senior vice presidents of magazines, the corporate director of magazine advertising sales, and the individual advertising sales directors and managers for each magazine.
Guests included presidents and other senior executives, media directors, advertising managers, and account managers from companies that advertised in Time Inc. publications. Companies included AT&T, Grey Advertising, McCann-Erickson, Ogilvy & Mather, Panasonic, and Seagram. Some years guests were given the option of taking the Time Inc. jet to and from the event.
Scope and Contents Note
The Time Inc. Invitational Records represent the Invitationals from 1983 to 1985, 1987, and 1989. Materials include planning binders, schedules of events, expense reports, bills, receipts, guest lists and invitations, response cards, rules of play, samples of printed material with the logo, bills and receipts, logistical materials such as maps to the accommodations and transportation arrangements, videotapes of events, digital material which may be duplicates of printed material, and other event planning material. The collection also contains undated branded material and souvenirs such as buttons, customized pencils, golf tees, bags, and sun visors.
Arrangement Note
Organized chronologically by year with undated materials at the end, and alphabetically within each year with general materials at the front.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers. Materials created within the past 35 years also may be subject to restriction on a case-by-case basis. Unreformatted audiovisual and digital material in the collection is not accessible. Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Time Inc. in 2015.
Related Archival Materials Note
This finding aid relates to just one record group of the Time Inc. Records. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the Guide to the Time Inc. Records (MS 3009). The Henry Luce Papers (MS 3014) were acquired with the Time Inc. Records. The collection of books acquired with the records are cataloged as the Time Inc. Reference Library.
Corporation records.; Corporations -- History.; Corporations -- New York (State) -- New York.; Golf -- Tournaments; Organization files.; Publishers and publishing -- New York (State) -- New York.; Tennis -- Tournaments; Time, inc. -- Archives.; Time, inc. -- History.
- General: History, 1982-1987 (Offsite-box 1474, Folder 1)
- 1983: General binder: Audiovisual-Memos (Offsite-box 1474, Folder 2-4)
- 1983: General binder: Directions-Suggestions (Offsite-box 1474, Folder 5-7)
- 1984: General (Offsite-box 1474, Folder 8-10)
- 1984: Master binder #1: Alexander-Transportation (Offsite-box 1474, Folder 11-12)
- 1984: Master binder #2: McClellan-Speaker (Offsite-box 1474, Folder 13-14)
- 1984: Master binder #3: Sports-Time Inc. Lists (Offsite-box 1475, Folder 1-2)
- 1984: Master binder #4: Gold-Samples (Offsite-box 1475, Folder 3-4)
- 1984: Master binder #5: Bills-Budget (Offsite-box 1475, Folder 5-6)
- 1984: General binder: Accommodations-Scenario (Offsite-box 1475, Folder 7-8)
- 1984: General binder: Planning (Offsite-box 1475, Folder 9)
- 1984: General binder: Timing-Participants (Offsite-box 1475, Folder 10)
- 1984: Samples (Offsite-box 1475, Folder 11)
- 1984: Videotapes: Golf (Offsite-box 1475, Folder 12)
  Scope and Contents Note
  Includes audiovisual material:
  2 videocassettes (VHS): 1/2 in.
- 1984: Videotapes: Tennis (Offsite-box 1475, Folder 13)
  1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in.
- 1985: Bag of Bag Tags (Offsite-box 4150, Folder 2)
- 1985: General (Offsite-box 1476, Folder 1-3)
- 1985: General binder: Audiovisual-Tennis (Offsite-box 1476, Folder 4-6)
- 1985: General binder: Gift-Transportation (Offsite-box 1476, Folder 7-9)
- 1985: General binder: Guest Information Packet? (Offsite-box 1476, Folder 10)
- 1985: Invitee List (Offsite-box 1476, Folder 11)
  Includes digital material:
  1 computer disc (floppy disk): 5 1/4 in. On label: "DW 2 Time Inc. Invitational Lists."
- 1985: Invitations (Offsite-box 1476, Folder 12-13)
- 1985: Lists (Offsite-box 1476, Folder 14-15)
- 1985: Responses (Offsite-box 1476, Folder 16)
- 1985: Samples (Offsite-box 1477, Folder 1-5)
- 1985: Videotapes: Putting and Teeing (Offsite-box 1477, Folder 6)
  1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On label: "Time Invitational 1985 Putting." On container sticky note: "No tennis. It POURED RAIN -couldn't play on grass courts -golfers went back out."
  1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On label: "Time Invitational-1985 Teeing."
- 1987: General (Offsite-box 1477, Folder 7)
- 1987: Book I binder: Background (Offsite-box 1477, Folder 8-10)
- 1987: Book II binder: Accommodations-Insurance (Offsite-box 1477, Folder 11-13)
  1 computer disc (floppy disk): 5 1/4 in. On label: "TII 1987 I." Label on sleeve: "Time Inc. Invitational (all business/activities) Disk: Full 1987."
  1 computer disc (floppy disk): 5 1/4 in. On label: "TII 1987 II." Label on sleeve: "Time Inc. Invitational 1987 - (Var. Memos) Disk: Full."
  1 computer disc (floppy disk): 5 1/4 in. On label: "Time Inc. Invitational 1987 III."
  1 computer disc (floppy disk): 5 1/4 in. On label: "TII - Sept. 28-29, 1987 IV."
- 1987: Address List (Offsite-box 1477, Folder 14)
- 1987: Expenses (Offsite-box 1477, Folder 15)
- 1987: Invitation List (Offsite-box 1478, Folder 1-2)
- 1987: Lists (Offsite-box 1478, Folder 3)
  1 computer disc (floppy disk): 5 1/4 in. On label: "#87-A. Maidout List Report."
  1 computer disc (floppy disk): 5 1/4 in. On label: "#87-B. Yesmaid - Nomaid - Delete - Report Formats. Maidstone 1987."
- 1987: Promotion List and Responses (Offsite-box 1478, Folder 4)
- 1987: Samples: General (Offsite-box 1478, Folder 5-6)
- 1987: Samples: Golf and Tennis Folders (Offsite-box 1478, Folder 7)
- 1989: General (Offsite-box 1478, Folder 8)
  1 computer disc (floppy disk): 5 1/4 in. On label: "Maidstone.dbf Maid.mft Maid.scr Maid.frm."
  1 computer disc (floppy disk): 5 1/4 in. On label: "Addl.dbf Oneplus.dbf."
  1 computer disc (floppy disk): 5 1/4 in. On label: "Backup 3/10/89."
  1 computer disc (floppy disk): 5 1/4 in. On label: "Bkup *.dbf *.scr Maidstone 1989."
  1 computer disc (floppy disk): 5 1/4 in. On label: "WPSO Oneplus.txt."
- 1989: General binder: Audiovisual-Ground Transportation (Offsite-box 1478, Folder 9-10)
  1 computer disc (floppy disk): 5 1/4 in. On label: "1989 Invitational DW3 Documents."
- 1989: Accommodations (Offsite-box 1478, Folder 11)
- 1989: Agenda (Offsite-box 1478, Folder 12)
- 1989: Box of Shirt Buttonsags (Offsite-box 4150, Item 1)
- 1989: Car Information (Offsite-box 1478, Folder 13)
- 1989: Cover Letters (Offsite-box 1478, Folder 14)
- 1989: Ferry Schedules (Offsite-box 1478, Folder 15)
- 1989: Flight Information (Offsite-box 1478, Folder 16)
- 1989: Golf Tour Information (Offsite-box 1478, Folder 16)
- 1989: Guest List (Offsite-box 1479, Folder 1)
- 1989: Host List (Offsite-box 1479, Folder 2)
- 1989: Invitee Lists (Offsite-box 1479, Folder 3-5)
  2 computer discs (floppy disk): 5 1/4 in.
- 1989: Mechanical Drawings for Signage and Printed Material (Offsite-box 2005)
- 1989: Reminder Note (Offsite-box 1479, Folder 6)
- 1989: Response Cards (Offsite-box 1479, Folder 7-10)
- 1989: Samples (Offsite-box 1479, Folder 11-15)
- 1989: Samples (Offsite-box 1480, Folder 1)
- 1989: Signs (Offsite-box 2005)
- 1989: Tennis Tour Information (Offsite-box 1480, Folder 2)
- 1989: Videotapes: Driving (Offsite-box 1480, Folder 3)
- Undated: Bag of Tees, Pencils, Ball Markers, and "Golfer's Pal" Tools (Offsite-box 4150, Folder 3)
- Undated: Golf Ball Bag (Offsite-box 4149, Item 1-7)
- Undated: Invitation Designs (Offsite-box 1480, Folder 4)
- Undated: Maps: Accommodations (Offsite-box 1480, Folder 5-11)
- Undated: Maps: Accommodations (Offsite-box 1481, Folder 1)
- Undated: Maps: East Hamptons (Offsite-box 1480, Folder 12)
- Undated: Maps: Westchester [to Time Inc. Aircraft] (Offsite-box 1480, Folder 13)
- Undated: Samples (Offsite-box 1480, Folder 14)
- Undated: Stationary (Offsite-box 1480, Folder 15)
- Undated: Tote Bag (Offsite-box 4149, Item 8-14)
- Undated: Visor (Offsite-box 4149, Item 15-26)
- Undated: Wristbands (Offsite-box 4149, Item 27-28)